[Gon] Knuckle is… He's so…
He's so kind.
[imperceptible]
[Gon] He doesn't have to teach me,
but still he keeps giving me advice.
One day, you will leave Gon behind to die.
you must stay out of Gon's life.
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
INTEREST X AND X CURSE
[narrator] As they prepare at long last
to challenge Knuckle and Shoot to battle,
Gon and Killua are deep in thought.
Gon, just as I promised,
I'll give it my all.
From the very beginning!
[Gon] I can't compete with him in speed.
Can't watch him.
I've got to feel him.
Through my aura!
[grunts]
[Knuckle] Pretty confused, aren't you?
I just lent you some of my aura.
That's A.P.R. Amortizing Power Redirector.
He's just here
to announce the interest increase.
It's time now. You've accrued interest.
[Gon] It still doesn't hurt, not one bit.
Of course, because I lent you 180 aura.
"180 aura" is simply
a numerical expression of life energy.
you'll be at a huge disadvantage.
Get it, fool?
It seems to me the max aura output
potential you can use through Ken
is about 1,800 aura.
When you're preparing for battle,
you usually expend approximately one aura
for every second.
that use a lot of Nen,
your rate of expended aura increases
by six to ten times.
The stronger your technique,
the more aura you use up.
That means
in an ordinary one-on-one fight,
you used up 12,000 aura.
[Gon whimpers]
[Knuckle] And you used Jajanken
four times.
Your AOP is around 1,800 aura.
But at the exact moment that
you yelled "Jan" to activate the attack,
the aura focused in your fist
was over 2,000.
That's due to its long windup
as well as your defensive sacrifice,
both of which are done
to focus aura in your fist.
A special provision covers such risks that
are often attributed to special attacks.
You spent around 5,500 aura in
your first three uses of Jajanken alone.
That puts your total consumed aura
at 17,500.
[Gon whimpers]
[Knuckle] As for the fourth shot,
right before your "Round 2" hit,
you ran out of energy.
Actually, following through
with the technique
uses twice the activation amount
which means you used about 4,000 aura.
The amount of aura used
is the same for Rock and Paper.
However, Paper falls into a category
that you haven't practiced much,
so you used up 4,000 aura
on a weak attack.
So, your maximum POP is
approximately 21,500 aura!
[Gon groans]
That wasn't the kind of attack
I was expecting.
[Knuckle laughs]
Not good with numbers, are you?
That's fine
because I'm just getting started.
-So you better listen, fool.
-Uh…
Whenever your total accumulation
of borrowed aura, including interest,
exceeds your current remaining
Potential Aura Output Power…
you will go bankrupt.
But the interest
just keeps on accumulating.
It's been a few minutes
since we started this fight,
[Knuckle] Even with the 390 aura
I've lent you,
you're under 20,000.
Your debt will continue to grow and grow.
Okay, then what?
A.P.R. becomes IRS:
Individual Ren Suppressor.
And haunts the debtor for 30 days
while the target remains
-in a state of Zetsu.
-[evil laughter]
In short, you won't be able to use
any Nen at all.
But it's too late to back out now, fool.
[Gon] That's why
he didn't use this ability before.
He held back for my sake.
Which increases your loan by 30.
So what are you gonna do now?
And until your debt is repaid,
and in full,
I won't suffer even the slightest damage
from your attacks.
[A.P.R.] It's time.
You have accrued interest.
[Knuckle] Come at me, fool!
If you just stand there,
you'll go bankrupt anyway!
You managed to land more hits.
But ultimately you only repaid about
100 of the aura that you owe me.
You still haven't even paid off
half the accrued interest.
I won't let you launch Jajanken again.
Once your debt goes over 10,000,
my victory's assured.
It's time now. You've accrued interest.
[breathes deeply]
[grunts softly]
[Killua] What the hell is that?
You should know,
I take no pleasure at all
in hurting people.
That's precisely why I chose an ability
that only activates
whenever damage is inflicted.
It causes me to be more selective.
I only use it
on those I don't mind hurting.
However…
The two of you
helped me realize something.
There are times
that it becomes necessary to fight
as a sign of respect for your opponent.
[Killua] Three floating hands?
They're floating, but how?
What's his ability?
Should I attack him first?
Calm down.
Use Gyo to check.
He's not using In.
Those three hands really are floating.
Which means,
more than likely, he's a Manipulator.
In other words…
[Biscuit] Every time you face an opponent
you perceive is stronger than you,
[Killua] I couldn't launch my attack.
My body, why can't I get it to move?
Is this my curse?
I wonder.
Stop. Don't think about it.
It's a bad habit.
His circumstances aside,
I must do my best to beat him.
Otherwise, I'm only insulting him.
[Killua] He's strong and fast.
He probably has me beat in every category.
[Illumi] That's right, Killua.
That's the way.
Don't fight an enemy you can't defeat.
Do you see your weakness?
You give up far too easily.
Even against enemies of equal strength,
you think, "He's tough,"
You would run,
because you think like a loser.
Forget it.
You know you'll never defeat him.
[Killua gasps]
My left eye.
But still, it's not good enough.
[Biscuit] You need to overcome
this bad habit right away.
Get way out of your comfort zone
and take a big risk for once
by challenging someone more powerful.
[Killua] I have to fight…
to win!
I'm blind on the left.
I've never truly fought,
and this is no different.
you must stay out of Gon's life.
Huh?
[yelling]
[Killua] I won't run anymore.
Take this.
Electric shock?
[gasps]
Now that's scary.
[heart beating]
[Killua] Never mind! Go!
[Illumi] Never over-pursue.
But how?
Stop.
How did you know?
[singer singing in Japanese]